uh really really excited cuz it's it's
hard to find guys that you know I'm not
going to say we're picky but you know we
we just have a a certain type that we
like and and he fits those boxes.
>> Really quick follow up just cuz you
brought up with with Tesla last year the
Senior Bowl, right? That's such a kind
of bang bang bang event, right? There's
three practices in a game. Like
>> what is it about that event where you
see a guy stand out there that that's
really a draw to you? Yeah, it's just um
you just know that um it look in and
credit to the guys that put the game
together, you know. Um it was it was Jim
Naggie in the past and you know uh he
passed the torch to Drew Fab and I
thought Drew Fab did a really nice job
putting together that roster. But it's
just seeing that type of competition uh
in in real raw practices uh for a whole
week, you know, and then playing the
game and you can just it's a lot of
stories that you can get from it.
There's some smaller school
developmental guys that get that have
rough days at the start of the week and
they kind of get better and then have a
good games and you know um not everybody
plays in the game. There's some guys
that you know a lot of guys opt out and
they play the whole game. I mean I think
that that says a lot but um Derek I
don't think he played in the game but uh
his his practices were were really
really good. But I knew for him what he
showed was not only did he um really
show that he was an improved pass
rusher, not just outside on the edge, uh
he can sub rush too, which is very
intriguing about him as well. I think
that was very underrated component of
his game. Um but um I I thought he did a
nice job proving at the Senior Bowl
versus top competition that he's a he's
a real pass rusher.
>> Your first go. Oh, I was going to say
your first two picks, offensive tackle
and edge rusher. Is that just a perfect
blend of what you need, but also that
what those were the guys you wanted?
>> Yeah. No, it it really did line up just
cuz um you know, like we've always said,
you know, we're we're just going to take
the best player. So, um you know, look,
if if there was I'm sure there was other
tackles that were available or there was
other, you know, edge rushers that were
available, but you know, but these were
the guys that we liked. So, um you know,
when it when it when it blends together
like that, it's it's it's really nice.
But, um yeah, uh could couldn't be
happier actually just from today and
yesterday. I know we still got a lot of
picks tomorrow or we lost one pick when
we traded up, but uh but I still feel
like we got um we got enough ammo to
still make a little bit of hay tomorrow
as well. But, um but yeah, I just I
didn't feel like it was any kind of
reaching for positions or anything like
that. I know that those were the popular
positions and all that stuff that they
were talked about for us, but um they
just happened to um be players that we
really liked.
>> Build off that and really your first,
you know, answer to Justin with the two,
but can you explain your vision for the
defensive line and how Derek, right,
like what he can do on the edge to
complete that because you have been, you
know, picky and and people in this room
have been on you a little bit, but
obviously you're looking for something,
you know, to
>> get on my ass now.
[laughter]
>> Probably not. I know. No. Um, no, it's a
good question. Uh, just because, um,
what what what what Derek is going to
bring, you know, to the defense is first
of all, like, you know, like you said,
you want to call it just being very
selective on the type of guys that we
get, you know. Um, you know, Hutch takes
a lot of snaps, man. you know, so just
to have another body that literally can
spell Hutch in that, you know, in that
in that rush rotation. Um, you know,
when you line up, you know, in in in
nickel and subdefense, you know, a guy
that can line up on the opposite, a guy
that can line up inside, um, you know,
Shep just going to put the guys in the
best position to what they do best. And
so, um, that's what he showed on tape is
he can set edges in the run game. He can
rush outside, he can rush inside. And
I'm quite sure that's what um how chef's
going to utilize him.
>> His um film, it seemed like whenever the
ball carrier was in his vicinity, he's a
really good tackler in space. Um maybe
not something that you think of as like
the primary skill set for an edge, but
what is it about what he does well there
and how valuable is that to you?
>> Yeah. Um well, you always say, you know,
you got to you got to get to third down.
You got to, you know, you got to earn
the right to run to rush the passer. And
so, um, those are those, uh, the the the
dirty work he doesn't mind to do. But
it's also a testament to his instincts
as well. And so, when you start talking
about, uh, guys that have good floors or
higher floors coming in, you know,
usually those guys are are instinctive
players. And that's what he is. He's
very instinctive in the run game. And,
um, um, it just it matters because you
just can't just be just Yeah. You know,
we talk about edge rusher, rush, rush,
rush. Well, yeah. I mean, we want to get
to the quarterback, but you can't just
get gashed all the way downfield either.
And so, um, I think that's a good
component to his game he's going to
bring.
>> How beneficial was it? How how I'm
sorry. How beneficial was it to see him,
uh, play in an NFL system? You know,
obviously they've had that Ravens style
defense since
>> Yeah. since.
>> Yeah. You know, Yeah. I mean, it's it's
it's very beneficial. Um, you know, it's
it's it's hard enough playing the all
the forecasting and projecting that we
have to do when we're evaluating these
prospects. So, when you see guys coming
out of these programs like a Michigan
or, you know, like what we've done in
the past at, you know, Alabama or Iowa
or, you know, Georgia, like those those
guys run NFL system. So, you know, um,
all the down to the alignment, the
assignment. So to be able to kind of
take a little bit of weight off your
back in terms of from a projection
standpoint and now you can kind of hone
in on, you know, what kind of physical
and mental makeup they have uh for us.
But it but it definitely helps because a
lot of the things that Derek did um it
might not be the exact same, but it's
I'm sure it's going to be a lot of
carryover.
>> Guys like uh Blake and Derek where you
said they've improved a lot over the
years. Like what are you looking for to
confirm that they can keep growing? Um
really just I would say their their
their work ethic and their football
character and um you know that's that's
all the work that all the scouts do
during during the year just um betting
sources and all of that. Now they have
to have the they have to have the proper
gears in their body to actually be able
to ascend. Um it kind of starts there
but there's a lot of guys that have the
gears in their body but they don't have
the other stuff. So that's why we just
put so much work and stock into the into
the intangibles and the work ethic and
all that. So you're talking about Derek
or Blake like when a guy's coachable,
you know, he loves football. They both
love football and you know and they're
and they're going to do everything in
their power to do to be a good football
player. Um you have to make sure they're
that first and then okay, you start
looking at the other stuff. So I I do
think they'll get better.
>> Trade up for someone. when you trade up
for Derek today, are you worried
someone's gonna get him? Was this a guy
that you woke up this morning, you know,
having that conviction to get? What was
what goes on in your head to make um I
would say he was one of the I would say
he was part of that cluster. He was part
of that cluster of guys that we were
targeting uh to today. So, he he was
already at at top of mind uh going up.
But just kind of paying attention to who
was in front of us, who was behind us.
um you know there was it felt like just
right in that area um there was multiple
edge rushers that were flying off. So um
and again I I always say like that's the
fascination of the draft. You don't
know. So you know Derek might have been
you know our you know three or four edge
rusher or what whatever it is for but he
was today he was our one um for for what
what was available. Uh but other teams
he could have been there seven or eight
and you you can't worry about that. You
just got to just get the guy that you
want.
>> You had to make sure you got somebody in
that cluster.
>> Yes. Yes. That's that's exactly what
we're doing.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> You guys you guys lost a lot of
production with Aadine 11 sacks. Um
>> is it too much to ask a rookie to
>> I'm glad you're asking me a question to
>> That's what I'm here for. Well, I feel
like when you don't like [laughter]
>> always just kind of
>> just just waiting.
>> I'm just waiting. I'm
>> tiger in the tall grass.
>> Good. Sorry.
>> Yeah. So, just when you lose that kind
of production, is it unreasonable to
expect the rookie to come close to
double digit sacks? You expect that to
come elsewhere? What are your
expectations for him as a rookie?
>> Yeah, look, he just needs to come in and
be who he is. um you know that's that's
not the reason why we drafted him Carlos
is that you know like he has to replace
uh Q's production and no it's not that
like if he does great you know um but
that's that's not why we draft him um I
we do expect that he can become that
player you know to meet that kind of
production um in time but that's not why
we we we we drafted him um but I will
say him coming on board he's going to
add to you know just the overall
production ction of our defense of just
adding more sacks and pressures getting
to the quarterback.
>> How do you how do you think that DJ and
Derek Moore complement each other? Like
maybe slightly different physical
profiles, statures. How do you see those
two guys? Want them and Derek Moore
complimenting each other?
>> Yeah, I I think they are good
compliments because they're both
physical players. Um they're they're a
little bit different. um you know, a
little bit different body types, but um
but I think they're both I mean, again,
that's why they're here is that, you
know, they fit the requirements of what
we look for at at that position. So,
they they both set good edges. Um they
they both can rush outside, they both
can rush inside. Um so, I'm quite sure
that, you know, um and and they're also
both good teammates, too. So, I'm I'm
I'm quite sure that um you know you know
DJ being the veteran of the group, I'm
sure that he's going to help Derek a
lot. But um but I I that it's it's a
it's a good question because I do think
there are some some similarities.
>> You guys are big on intangibles, too,
obviously. What does he have? Is it is
it similar to Miller different than the
two guys that you picked?
>> Yeah. Well, first of all, it starts with
their passion for football. You know, um
they they they both love football. um
you know, they'll um they're they're
going to do everything they got to do to
make sure that their body is right, that
they're in shape. Um that they're
they're they're being coachable and that
they're laying it all out out on the
line. And um you know, look, there's
nobody that's that's perfect or anything
like like that. Everybody has mistakes,
but uh the passion for football is is
numero uno for us. And so um that that
that's where they're very similar. They
they they both love football. curious
about your coach's impact in your
overall scouting process. I know you
bring them in kind of towards the end of
the process and get their their opinion.
So, Coach Rogers and Shep, you know, how
did they maybe help you land on this
player if at all?
>> Yeah, they they they're a huge help on
the vision aspect. Um and obviously, you
know, they they evaluate the the players
and, you know, we we have good meetings,
we have good dialogue. Um cuz there's
some guys that, you know, um we we'll
see differently. you know, there's some
guys that maybe um that I might like the
football player, but you know, just not
really sure where he's going to fit, you
know. So, um, but I will say this, what
what's been cool, um, about Shep is, uh,
his his open-mindedness in terms of
that, uh, if a guy has a skill set or a
let's call it a superpower, um, he's
he's not going to be rigid and say,
"Well, he doesn't fit in this box, so he
can't like this guy does this well, then
we're going to find a place for him to
to do that." So, um, but they're they're
they're very helpful. Their evaluations,
their experience, and then just also
just fitting that vision.
>> Were you nervous? Baltimore was going to
grab him.
>> Was going to grab him. Is that what you
They were right after you guys, the
Ravens.
>> Um, you know, I don't know if they
wanted him or not. Um, but, you know,
kind of got a sense that they were in
the edge rusher market though. Yeah.
>> But just, you know, about us getting on
you a little bit about getting a
defensive end. Was it uh beyond, you
know, I mean, I know, you know, getting
him was most important, but just to get
a defensive end, was that nice to get us
off your back or
>> No, that that def was definitely an
afterthought after we after we picked
them. But I did think about it. We're
walking down. I was like, finally, I'm
going to the podium. We draft. It's been
I don't know what 22 or something. We
did it. So, um, but no, um, again, look,
we just, you know, it just, again, I
can't say it probably sound like a
broken record. Um, it's not something
that we have been ignoring. It just, it
just, it just has to line up. Um, like
I've said the years past, year before.
Um, look, we could the easiest thing is
to draft a defensive end every single
round, every single year. That that's
very easy to do, but you want him to be
a good player and produce. Well, then
now you're dealing with something else,
you know? So, um, that's that's that's
what the hope is for, um, for Derek and,
um, you know, we we feel good about it.
>> Do you think there's maybe still an
opportunity to be active tonight? I
mean, there's still 36 37 picks.
>> We're probably done. I'm not going to
hide anything. I mean, I'll go back. I
got my phone in my pocket. If someone,
you know, I'm not going to turn anything
down, but, you know, I don't I don't
foresee us doing anything else for the
rest of the night. How well do you sleep
on a night like this when you've got
each of the trenches really addressed
and and settled?
>> Very well. Very well. Yes. Good
question. Um yeah, just you know, it's
not again it's not just Yes. Like the
trenches are so important and you know,
we're all about, you know, building it
from the inside out, but it's just, you
know, when you when you get the guys
that you love and they happen to play in
the trenches as well, um that's just a
little bit added bonus. But um but we'll
definitely sleep good at night. Sleep
even better because I didn't wait till
the end of the night to talk to you
guys.
>> You guys are sleep when you're taking uh
you know a high value pick like first
and second round. How important is it to
have you know faith and uh a familiarity
with the programs that you're I mean
because you you have taken guys from
Alabama, Georgia, Michigan in these top
uh regions in the draft. I mean how
important is that familiarity? I mean,
it definitely Yeah, it it it definitely
helps. Um, it's it's not the not the end
all be all. Like, look, if there's a if
there's a kid from a small school, you
know, that's just a really really good
football player that he was worth the
value of drafting in the second round or
first round, then we're going to do it.
Now, our our work and our process, our
preparation is not going to change,
whatever that was. But maybe it's time
to go. But our um but in terms of our
our our vetting and our work and you
know um our thoroughess and watching as
much film as possible and you know doing
all our work on the front end with you
know our sources and the scouts doing
the work whether they're at you know
North Carolina ENT or they're at
University of Georgia where we're going
to take the same process but I do
understand you know um guys that come
out of certain programs you just kind of
know what they've been through and they
have a track record and history of
producing good players Any other edge
rushers you're looking at? [laughter]
>> Maybe. Maybe. We'll see. Got a lot of
picks tomorrow, so we'll see. Yeah.
>> Something tomorrow for Rod or for what's
what's on the uh fastening.
>> Yeah.
>> I just going to wear what I what I wear
with Dave, man.
>> All right, guys. Thanks. Appreciate it.
>> Appreciate it. [music]
>> [music]
[music]
>> Hey,
hey, hey.
[music]
>> [music]